>> TONIGHT, IT'S THE SHOCKING
CONCLUSION OF
"THE BACHELORETTE."
>> LOVE IS THE CLOSEST THING TO
MAGIC THERE IS.
>> HANNAH'S JOURNEY TO FIND LOVE
IS ABOUT TO COME TO AN EMOTIONAL
END.
>> THIS WEEK HAS BEEN THE
HARDEST DECISION OF MY LIFE.
>> HANNAH IS IN LOVE WITH TYLER.
>> HANNAH IS LOUD AND PROUD, AND
THAT'S WHAT THIS IS RIGHT HERE.
>> AND JED.
>> WE HAVE BEEN A CONSTANT, ABLE
TO COME BACK TO WHERE WE STARTED
NO MATTER WHAT.
>> AND TONIGHT, HANNAH MUST
CHOOSE.
>> I CAN'T DO THIS.
I --
CAN YOU STOP THE CAR?
[GRUNTS]
I REALLY CAN'T DO THIS.
HOW WOULD YOU EVER BE READY TO
BE ENGAGED?
LIKE -- LIKE, WHAT?
LIKE, I'VE BEEN DOING ALL THE
FREAKING STEPS AND, LIKE, KNOW
WHAT I WANT.
>> THE EMOTIONAL AND SHOCKING
CONCLUSION OF "THE BACHELORETTE"
IS ABOUT TO BEGIN.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF I WANT THIS.
I DON'T KNOW.
>> IT'S LIVE AND IT ALL STARTS
RIGHT NOW.
THANK YOU.
HELLO, BACHELOR NATION, I'M
CHRIS HARRISON.
WELCOME TO THE DRAMATIC LIVE
FINALE OF "THE BACHELORETTE."
TWO MAN, TYLER AND JED, ARE
TOTALLY IN LOVE WITH HANNAH, AND
THEY ARE READY TO PROPOSE TO
HER, BUT THE SHOCKING CONCLUSION
TO HANNAH'S JOURNEY TO FIND LOVE
IS ONE THAT NOBODY COULD HAVE
SEEN COMING, NOT HANNAH, NOT
EVEN ME.
TONIGHT, WE'LL WITNESS GREAT
LOVE, INCREDIBLE TRUST, AND
UNFORTUNATELY, THE MASSIVE
DESTRUCTIVE FORCES OF LIES AND
BETRAYAL.
WE'LL ALSO SEE A PROPOSAL THAT,
IN RETROSPECT, CAN ONLY BE
DESCRIBED AS CRINGEWORTHY.
I HOPE YOU'RE READY, BACHELOR
NATION, BECAUSE HERE WE GO.
♪
>> IT'S A WEIRD FEELING THAT,
EVEN THOUGH IT IS THE END, THIS
FEELS A LOT LIKE THE FIRST NIGHT
BECAUSE I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S
NEXT, BUT I'M EXCITED.
SINCE THE BEGINNING, I HAVE
CHANGED.
I AM A DIFFERENT WOMAN.
YOU HAVE TO SHOW EVERY LAYER OF
YOU, THE GOOD AND THE BAD, TO
SOMEBODY, IF THEY'RE GOING TO
SPEND THE REST OF THEIR LIFE
WITH YOU, AND I SHOWED
EVERYTHING, AND IT FELT AMAZING.
LIKE, I FELT TRULY FREE.
JUST TO THINK OF THE GIRL I USED
TO BE, JUST A REALLY DEPENDENT
GIRL AND SAD ON THE INSIDE
BECAUSE -- NEEDED VALIDATION
FROM EVERYONE AND NEVER FELT
ENOUGH.
AND IT'S JUST -- TO HAVE, LIKE,
JUST A WHOLE DIFFERENT MIND-SET
OF WHO I AM AND WHAT I NEED IN
LIFE WHERE I DON'T NEED A MAN IN
MY LIFE BUT I WANT ONE TO
EXPERIENCE THE FULL LIFE THAT I
HAVE WITH ME.
THEY SAY THAT LOVE IS THE
CLOSEST THING TO MAGIC THERE IS.
I AM ONE OF THE LUCKY FEW THAT
GET TO EVER EXPERIENCE SOMETHING
SO MAGICAL.
THE UNKNOWN IS STILL THERE, BUT
I KNOW I HAVE SOMEBODY TO HOLD
MY HAND THROUGH IT.
♪
I HAVE BEEN FALLING IN LOVE WITH
BOTH TYLER AND JED THROUGH THIS.
I WAS HOPEFUL FOR LOVE; NOW I
KNOW THERE IS LOVE.
BUT IT IS SOMETHING THAT I AM
TAKING -- STILL TAKING A CHANCE,
BECAUSE MY FUTURE RELIES ON A
CHOICE THAT I MAKE.
>> HOW YOU DOING?
>> HI.
I'M NEIL LANE.
>> TYLER CAMERON.
>> NICE TO MEET YOU.
BIG DAY?
>> YES, HUGE DAY.
>> FROM THE VERY START, I WAS
DRAWN TO TYLER.
TYLER ALWAYS PUTS ME FIRST, AND
HE MAKES ME FEEL STRONG.
>> I DON'T KNOW, MAN, THIS IS
TOUGH.
HANNAH IS LOUD AND PROUD, AND --
AND THAT'S WHAT THIS IS RIGHT
HERE, YOU KNOW?
>> WITH TYLER, I FEEL REALLY
SECURE THAT HE WOULD DO WHATEVER
IT TAKES TO HAVE A HAPPY LIFE
TOGETHER.
♪
WITH JED, HE'S ALWAYS BEEN
SOMEBODY THAT I COULD TALK TO
FOR HOURS AND HOURS AND BE SUPER
SILLY WITH BUT ALSO HAVE DEEP
CONVERSATIONS WITH.
>> THIS ONE ALMOST REPRESENTS
OUR LOVE MORE JUST BECAUSE OF
THE OVAL SHAPE.
IT'S KIND OF MORE OF A CONSTANT.
AND WE'VE BEEN A CONSTANT, ABLE
TO COME BACK TO WHERE WE STARTED
NO MATTER WHAT.
>> I FEEL LIKE JED IS AS HONEST
WITH ME AS I AM WITH HIM,
WHICH -- THAT'S WHAT YOU WANT IN
A LIFE PARTNER.
♪
WE'VE ALL, LIKE, HAD MOMENTS IN
OUR LIFE THAT HAVE REALLY
DEFINED US, AND THIS IS A
DEFINING MOMENT TRULY.
THE BEST THINGS IN LIFE ARE THE
HARDEST THINGS IN LIFE TOO, AND
THIS WEEK HAS BEEN THE HARDEST
DECISION OF MY LIFE.
♪
YOU KNOW, IT'S SO HARD, BECAUSE
THE LIFE WITH TYLER IS DIFFERENT
THAN JED, AND I AM CONFLICTED IN
MY HEART.
I WAS HOPEFUL THAT I WOULD HAVE
CLARITY, BUT, LIKE, TODAY,
LIKE...
[SIGHS]
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T WANT TO NOT BE 100% SURE
AND THEN MAKE THE WRONG
DECISION.
♪
MM-MM.
I CAN'T DO THIS.
I --
CAN YOU STOP THE CAR?
WILL YOU PLEASE STOP THE CAR?
[GRUNTS]
>> ARE YOU OKAY?
>> NO.
[LAUGHING]
I REALLY CAN'T DO THIS.
THAT REALLY HURT.
>> ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
>> NO, I'M NOT.
I JUST FREAKING --
>> IT'S JUST A BIG DAY.
>> THINK YOU CAN DO THIS?
>> YEAH.
[WHISTLES]
I'M READY.
♪
IT'S A WEIRD DAY.
IT'S A WEIRD FEELING, YOU KNOW,
KNOWING THAT SOMETHING'S ENDING
TODAY, BUT SOMETHING'S BEGINNING
TODAY.
I'M SO EXCITED ABOUT TODAY AND
WHAT MY FUTURE'S GOING TO LOOK
LIKE, BUT I DO HAVE TO CLOSE THE
DOOR TO THE PAST.
IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
♪
JED AND TYLER HAVE PIECES OF MY
HEART, AND I DON'T KNOW HOW I
TELL SOMEBODY TODAY THAT THEY'RE
NOT ENOUGH, BECAUSE THAT'S NOT
TRUE.
THERE'S REALLY NO GOOD WAY TO
SAY THAT TO SOMEBODY.
THE MAN THAT I HAVE TO END
THINGS WITH TODAY IS NOT GOING
TO EXPECT IT.
♪
>> TYLER.
>> CHRIS.
>> WELCOME.
>> THANK YOU.
>> HOW'RE YOU DOING?
>> DOING AMAZING.
>> HOW YOU FEELING?
>> SO EXCITED.
THIS LOVE IS FOREVER RIGHT HERE.
EVERY TIME I TRY TO TALK ABOUT
IT, I JUST LOSE MY WORDS AND I
GET ALL CHEESY AND GOOFY, AND
HERE I GO AGAIN.
BUT I LOOK INTO HER EYES, I FEEL
SO CONFIDENT AND I CAN TAKE ON
THE WORLD AND DO EVERYTHING.
>> ALL RIGHT, SIR, THIS IS WHERE
I LEAVE YOU.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> HANNAH IS WAITING RIGHT
THROUGH THERE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> GOOD LUCK.
>> THANK YOU.
THE FUTURE HOLDS FOR US A LOVE
AND A BOND THAT WILL NEVER
BREAK.
THAT'S IT FOR ME.
I'M DOWN FOR IT.
LIKE, I WANT HER MORE THAN
ANYTHING I'VE EVER WANTED IN MY
LIFE.
THE WOMAN OF MY DREAMS.
YOU LOOK ABSOLUTELY GORGEOUS.
>> THANK YOU.
HEY.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
>> GOOD.
[SIGHS]
>> HERE WE ARE.
>> IT'S SO CRAZY WE'RE HERE,
RIGHT?
>> I KNOW.
WE HAVE LITERALLY REACHED THE
PEAK OF OUR JOURNEY.
>> I KNOW.
>> HANNAH BROWN, FROM THE MOMENT
I MET YOU, YOU'VE CAPTIVATED MY
SOUL.
I ALWAYS KNEW THE MAN I WANTED
TO BE, AND I KNEW I WOULD GET
THERE ONE DAY, BUT I DIDN'T KNOW
HOW.
AND THEN I MET YOU.
I REALIZED THE MAN I WAS MEANT
TO BE TOOK YOU TO PUSH ME TO GET
THERE.
I HAVE GROWN SO MUCH
EMOTIONALLY, SPIRITUALLY, AND SO
MADLY IN LOVE.
I KNOW OUR LOVE WAS SLOW TO
START, BUT IT IS A LIGHT THAT
WILL BURN FOREVER, JUST LIKE THE
LIGHTHOUSE WE MET UNDER IN
JUPITER, FLORIDA.
I STARTED FALLING IN LOVE WITH
YOU THE FIRST MOMENT I GOT TO
HOLD YOU AND DANCE WITH YOU AND
HAVE YOU IN MY ARMS ON OUR FIRST
DATE.
>> TYLER...
>> THIS ISN'T IT.
>> [EXHALES SLOWLY]
JUST -- JUST --
I AM SO LUCKY TO BE LOVED BY YOU
AND TO FEEL THAT.
YOU HAVE SUPPORTED ME.
YOU HAVE BEEN SO SWEET AND
STRONG FOR ME AND DONE
EVERYTHING THAT I'VE ASKED AND
MORE AND LOVED ME SO MUCH.
AND MY LIFE WITH YOU WOULD BE...
AMAZING.
AND WHEN I TOLD YOU I WAS
FALLING IN LOVE WITH YOU, I MEAN
IT.
BUT I LOVE SOMEONE ELSE.
I'M SO SORRY.
I DON'T...
>> IT'S GOING TO HURT, BUT I'M
STILL GOING TO BE YOUR BIGGEST
FAN ROOTING FOR YOU.
I WISH YOU AND JED NOTHING BUT
SUCCESS.
I REALLY MEAN THAT.
♪
>> I'M SO SORRY.
>> I WISH YOU A PERFECT SUCCESS
WITH JED.
YOU GUYS WILL BE GREAT.
>> CAN I WALK YOU OUT?
>> YEAH.
♪
[INDISTINCT]
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I'LL SEE YOU.
♪
I THOUGHT THIS WAS IT.
IT FEELS LIKE A MILLION
UPPERCUTS TO THE GUT RIGHT NOW.
I'VE NEVER BEEN ONE TO BE ABLE
TO OPEN UP, AND IT REALLY TOOK
HANNAH TO PULL IT OUT OF ME.
AND I REALIZED ONCE IT WAS OUT
OF ME HOW AMAZING IT FEELS TO BE
OPEN.
AND -- AND I JUST -- THESE
FEELINGS THAT I'VE HAD, LIKE, I
HAVEN'T HAD FOR ANYONE THIS
STRONG, YOU KNOW?
I'M HURT.
I THOUGHT IT WAS HANNAH, BUT
THAT'S NOT THE CASE.
♪
[APPLAUSE]
>> THAT WAS DIFFICULT TO WATCH.
I KNOW THERE ARE A LOT OF TYLER
FANS HERE IN THE AUDIENCE
TONIGHT WHO ARE DEVASTATED BY
WHAT JUST HAPPENED, AND I'M SURE
THE SAME AT HOME.
TYLER IS GOING TO JOIN YOU HERE
ON STAGE A LITTLE BIT LATER
WHERE HE WILL SEE HANNAH FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE THAT HEARTBREAK
AND GOODBYE.
BUT BEFORE WE GET TO THAT,
HANNAH IS NOW LEFT WITH ONE MAN,
AT JED.
HOW THE HILL HER STORY END?
CAN JED GIVE HANNAH THE LOVE AND
TRUST SHE NEEDS AND A HUSBAND?
WE'LL FIND OUT NEXT.
>> IT BREAKS MY HEART TO KNOW
THAT I BROKE TYLER'S HEART
TODAY.
I HOPE TYLER FORGIVES ME AND
KNOWS HOW MUCH HE ALLOWED ME TO
JUST BE MYSELF.
AS HARD AS THAT WAS, TODAY I
HAVE CLARITY.
I PRAYED FOR PEACE TODAY FOR MY
DECISION AND MY FUTURE.
I'VE BEEN WAITING MY WHOLE LIFE
TO HAVE MY HAPPY ENDING.
♪
>> I'M ABOUT TO ASK HANNAH TO
MARRY ME.
IT JUST ALL KIND OF HIT ME, HOW
AMAZING THIS COULD BE.
I FEEL EXCITED AND SCARED.
NERVOUS.
THIS IS THE BIGGEST DAY OF MY
LIFE.
♪
>> JED, WELCOME.
>> THANK YOU.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> GOOD LUCK.
HANNAH IS WAITING FOR YOU RIGHT
DOWN THAT PATH.
>> THANK YOU.
♪
HEY, YOU.
>> HEY.
YOU LOOK SO HANDSOME.
>> YOU LOOK BEAUTIFUL.
WHEN I MET YOU, I WANTED TO SEE
A LIGHT INSIDE OF YOU, AND I
WANTED TO KNOW THE DEEPEST PART
OF YOU.
THE WAY THAT YOU'VE MADE ME FEEL
AND THE LIGHT THAT YOU HAVE
INSIDE OF YOU IS EVEN BRIGHTER
THAN I COULD HAVE EVER IMAGINED.
YOU KNOW, I NEVER THOUGHT I
COULD LOVE SOMEBODY LIKE THIS
THIS FAST, AND THOUGH THE OTHER
SIDE IS KIND OF UNSURE, RIGHT
HERE IS FOR SURE, AND I KNOW
THAT I LOVE YOU.
AND TALKING IS HARD SOMETIMES
FOR ME, SO...
♪
♪ AFTER ALL THAT YOU'VE BEEN
THROUGH ♪
♪ AND THOSE TIMES YOU WISH YOU
KNEW ♪
♪ WHO WAS ON THE OTHER SIDE OF
ALL THOSE RESTLESS NIGHTS ♪
♪ WE ALWAYS KNEW IT'S ME AND
YOU ♪
>> [LAUGHS]
>> ♪ TIME STANDS STILL FOR US
♪ IT'S HAPPENED MORE THAN ONCE
♪ AND EVERY TIME WE'RE HOLDING
HANDS AND DANCING IN THE SUN ♪
♪ BABY, TIME STANDS STILL FOR
US ♪
>> I REALLY LIKED THAT.
I DON'T HAVE A SONG, BUT I'D
LIKE TO SAY SOME STUFF.
>> OKAY.
>> [SIGHS]
YOU KNOW, I'VE ALWAYS PRAYED FOR
MY FUTURE HUSBAND, AND AS A
LITTLE GIRL, I CAN REMEMBER
SITTING IN MY ROOM.
I NEVER KNEW WHO I WAS PRAYING
FOR, BUT I WAS ALWAYS JUST
WONDERING WHAT THEIR LIFE WAS
LIKE, WHAT THEY WERE DOING, WHAT
THEIR PASSIONS WERE.
I SOMETIMES QUESTIONED WHY GOD
HAS ALLOWED THINGS TO HAPPEN IN
MY LIFE THE WAY THEY DID,
STRUGGLE THE WAY I'VE STRUGGLED
AND HAD THE HEARTBREAKS I'VE HAD
AND WHY THIS WAS MY JOURNEY.
THERE WERE SO MANY TIMES IN MY
LIFE WHERE I THOUGHT THAT IT
WOULD BE IT AND IT WASN'T, AND I
DIDN'T UNDERSTAND WHY.
BUT IT'S LED ME TO THIS MOMENT.
IT'S LED ME TO YOU.
I'VE BEEN PRAYING FOR THIS
MOMENT FOR A LONG TIME.
I'VE BEEN PRAYING FOR YOU.
YOU'VE SUPPORTED ME.
YOU'VE LOVED ME.
YOU'VE CHALLENGED ME.
YOU'VE MOVED ME.
AND IT'S MADE ME LOVE YOU SO, SO
MUCH.
AND I AM IN COMPLETE LOVE WITH
YOU.
I LOVE YOU, JED WYATT.
>> I HAVE LIVED 25 YEARS OF MY
LIFE WITHOUT YOU, AND I DON'T
WANT TO GO ANOTHER DAY OF MY
LIFE WITHOUT YOU BEING ALL MINE.
HANNAH...
>> YES?
>> WILL YOU MARRY ME?
>> YES.
♪
[LAUGHS]
I LOVE YOU.
I DIDN'T EVEN LOOK AT THE RING
REALLY, BUT I'M SURE IT'S REALLY
PRETTY.
OH, MY GOSH.
[LAUGHS]
>> OH, MY GOD.
>> WE DID IT.
WOW.
>> IT'S US.
>> WHEE!
OH, THERE'S ONE MORE THING WE
HAVE TO DO.
JED...
>> YES?
>> [LAUGHS]
WILL YOU ACCEPT THIS ROSE?
>> YES.
>> MY FINAL ROSE.
♪
>> IT'S YOU.
>> [SIGHS]
>> WE'RE ENGAGED!
>> WHOO!
I'M ENGAGED, YOU'RE ENGAGED,
WE'RE ENGAGED.
>> WE'RE ENGAGED TOGETHER.
>> WOW.
>> WE'RE GETTING MARRIED.
>> WHOA.
I LOVE YOU.
>> I LOVE YOU, BABY.
>> I TOLD HIM I LOVED HIM TODAY.
>> YEP.
I'VE BEEN WAITING FOR THAT FOR A
LONG TIME.
I'M JUST -- I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT TO SAY.
>> I DON'T EITHER.
>> I DON'T CARE.
I JUST WANT TO BE WITH YOU.
>> ♪ HE IS MR. RIGHT, BOY ♪
♪ YOU ARE MR. RIGHT, MMM ♪
[APPLAUSE]
>> WELL, THERE IT IS, AND JED
GOT ENGAGED AND AFTER A LONG AND
DIFFICULT JOURNEY, HANNAH THINKS
SHE HAS FOUND HER SOULMATE, AND
JED HAS PROMISED FOREVER TO HER
WITH A LIFE FULL OF LOVE,
PASSION, AND TRUST, AND HE
SEALED IT WITH A SONG.
[LAUGHTER]
UNFORTUNATELY, THAT'S NOT WHERE
THIS JOURNEY ENDS.
WHAT HAPPENS NEXT IS A STORY OF
BROKEN PROMISES AND BROKEN
HEARTS.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE ARE GOING
TO SHOW YOU THE SHOCKING EVENTS
THAT OCCURRED SINCE THAT LAST
HAPPY DAY IN GREECE.
LET ME SAY IT THIS WAY.
JED IS ABOUT TO FACE THE MUSIC.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> HELLO.
>> WE ARE IN GREECE.
>> YEP.
>> AND THIS IS OUR FIRST
VIDEO --
>> TOGETHER.
>> THAT WE'VE MADE TOGETHER
SINCE WE'VE BEEN OFFICIALLY
TOGETHER.
>> SO...
>> UM, IT'S PRETTY COOL.
>> IT'S REALLY COOL.
MY RING IS VERY PRETTY.
>> WE'RE -- WE'RE, LIKE,
ACTUALLY ENGAGED.
>> ACTUALLY.
>> AND WE ARE SITTING HERE JUST
TRYING TO TAKE IT IN.
AND OUR VIEW IS STUNNING.
>> OH, MY GOSH.
MRS. WYATT.
[LAUGHS]
>> SHE'S GOING TO BE A WYATT.
I LOVE YOU.
>> I LOVE YOU.
WHEN I CHOSE JED AT THE END AND
HE GOT DOWN ON ONE KNEE, I WAS
EXCITED.
THE FIRST THOUGHT THAT WENT
THROUGH MY HEAD WAS, THIS IS IT.
HE IS SO REAL WITH ME AND I'M
SO REAL WITH HIM, AND THAT'S
WHAT I WANTED FROM THE VERY
START.
JED AND I HAVE HAD SOME REALLY
GREAT TIMES.
WE'VE HAD SILLY DANCE PARTIES.
WE PLAYED STUPID GAMES.
I MEAN, STUPID FUN STUFF THAT I
NEED IN A RELATIONSHIP.
I CAME ON THE SHOW HOPING TO
FIND LOVE AND WANTING TO SPEND
MY LIFE WITH SOMEONE, AND WITH
JED, I WAS SO HAPPY BECAUSE I
THOUGHT I WAS GETTING THIS
PERSON THAT I CAN SPEND LIFE
WITH WHO WAS SWEET AND SINCERE
AND HONEST.
AND...
THAT'S NOT BEEN THE CASE.
THE SECOND NIGHT AFTER WE GOT
ENGAGED, JED TELLS ME THAT HE
HAD BEEN HANGING OUT WITH THIS
GIRL BEFORE HE LEFT TO COME TO
THE SHOW.
AND I WAS LIKE, "WHEN WAS THIS?"
AND I REMEMBER HIM SAYING,
"A WEEK BEFORE THE SHOW."
AND I WAS LIKE, "OKAY, SO YOU
BROKE IT OFF?"
HE SAID YES.
HE TOLD ME IT WAS NOTHING.
IT WAS HARD TO HEAR, BUT I TRIED
TO LET THAT GO.
AND THEN A FEW WEEKS LATER, I
GET NEWS THAT THERE WAS A
"PEOPLE" MAGAZINE ARTICLE THAT
WAS OUT, AND I START READING IT,
AND IT WAS NOT THE SAME STORY
THAT I WAS TOLD.
THE ARTICLE SAID THAT HE DIDN'T
REALLY END THE RELATIONSHIP
BEFORE HE CAME HERE.
THE EXTENT OF THAT AND WHAT WAS
WITHHELD FROM ME AFTER I'VE
ALREADY SAID YES IS NOT OKAY.
JED HAS MUDDIED THE WATERS OF
OUR FUTURE TOGETHER, AND IT'S
NOT WHAT I THOUGHT I SAID YES
TO.
♪
I DON'T KNOW IF HE UNDERSTANDS
THE DEPTH OF HOW MUCH THIS HURTS
ME.
THIS LAST WEEK HAS BEEN THE
HARDEST WEEK OF ME EITHER
SCREAMING OR CRYING OR FALLING
TO MY KNEES, LIKE, NOT KNOWING
WHAT TO DO.
I DON'T KNOW HOW I FEEL ABOUT
JED AT THIS POINT.
I LOVE THE PERSON I GOT ENGAGED
TO.
I DON'T KNOW HOW I FEEL ABOUT
THIS PERSON.
JED IS ON HIS WAY TO MEET ME
NOW.
I MEAN, OF COURSE I HAVE
QUESTIONS, AND I DON'T KNOW HOW
THIS IS GOING TO GO, BUT IT'S A
REALLY IMPORTANT CONVERSATION.
[KNOCKS]
[APPLAUSE]
>> HI.
>> HEY.
>> MISSED YOU.
>> I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHERE TO
START.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHERE TO
WHY DID YOU WAIT UNTIL ALL THIS
HAPPENED?
>> FOR?
>> TO TELL ME.
OR NOT EVEN TO TELL ME, TO LET
ME FIND OUT WHAT ACTUALLY
HAPPENED.
>> WELL, BECAUSE THERE WAS TWO
VERY DIFFERENT VIEWS OF WHAT
ACTUALLY HAPPENED.
SO I GUESS I'LL START WITH THAT
SO YOU CAN HAVE, LIKE, THE
FULL -- THE FULL THING.
>> WHEN WAS THE BEGINNING?
>> IN OCTOBER.
LIKE, LATE OCTOBER.
>> OKAY.
>> WHEN I MET HER, I WAS VERY
SINGLE.
I WAS WITH -- GOING OUT WITH MY
FRIENDS, AND JUST BEING YOUNG,
HAVING FUN, AND I DIDN'T FEEL
LIKE IT WAS AN EXCLUSIVE THING.
I WAS DATING AROUND, AND IT
NEVER FELT LIKE A RELATIONSHIP
TO ME.
>> SO YOU WERE NOT JUST DATING
HER, YOU WERE DATING OTHER GIRLS
TOO?
LIKE, DID YOU TELL THEM?
>> NO, SHE WAS, LIKE, THE ONE
THAT I WAS, LIKE -- I JUST SPENT
THE MOST TIME WITH HER AND WE
HUNG OUT, LIKE, A FEW TIMES.
>> WHAT IS HANGING OUT A FEW
TIMES?
LIKE, WHAT IS THAT?
IS THAT, LIKE, YOU MEET HER AND
THEN YOU, LIKE, HOOK -- LIKE,
WHAT -- I JUST WANT TO KNOW WHAT
THAT IS, LIKE, TRULY.
JUST -- THIS IS THE TIME TO BE
AS BLUNT AS I AM.
>> YEAH.
WE HAD GONE TO SOME FRIENDS
TOGETHER, WE HAD GONE TO A
DINNER TOGETHER, THEN AFTER
DINNER TOGETHER, WE HAD SLEPT
TOGETHER.
AND SHE HAD JUST CAME TO MY
HOUSE AND I THINK WE WATCHED A
MOVIE.
>> AND THEN SLEPT TOGETHER
PROBABLY.
>> PROBABLY.
AFTER THAT, WE TOOK A TRIP TO
GATLINBURG AND STAYED AT A
CABIN.
>> JUST Y'ALL TWO?
>> HUH?
>> YEAH, I GOT A CABIN FOR FREE.
>> OKAY.
GO.
>> YOU TOLD ME TO TELL THE
TRUTH.
>> I WANT YOU TO TELL THE TRUTH.
BUT I'M ALSO GOING TO REACT TO
THE TRUTH, AND BE LIKE, WHAT THE
FREAK?
>> OKAY.
>> AND YOU'RE NOT DATING?
OKAY, GO AHEAD.
>> THERE WAS NOT A LABEL ON IT.
I NEVER WAS LIKE, THIS IS MY
GIRLFRIEND.
>> WERE YOU, LIKE, STILL HOOKING
UP WITH OTHER CHICKS?
>> YEAH.
I WAS.
>> LIKE -- OKAY.
YOU GO TO GATLINBURG.
>> WE GO TO GATLINBURG, WE LEAVE
THE CABIN, AND IT'S, LIKE, CLOSE
TO MY PARENT'S HOUSE.
THEY WERE LIKE, STOP BY,
WHATEVER.
SO WE STOPPED BY, SHE MET MY
PARENTS.
WE GO BACK TO NASHVILLE, LIFE
GOES ON.
JANUARY ROLLS AROUND, IT'S MY
BIRTHDAY.
I'VE NEVER HAD ANYONE THROW ME A
SURPRISE BIRTHDAY PARTY.
SHE HAS, LIKE, RALLIED ALL MY
FRIENDS.
THERE WAS, LIKE, A CAKE, AND I
JUST GET EXCITED OVER ALL THAT
STUFF.
I WAS JUST LIKE, OH, MY GOSH.
LIKE, I DIDN'T EXPECT ANYONE TO
DO ANYTHING.
AND SHE WAS LIKE, "AND I GOT YOU
THIS."
WHICH -- FROM HER PARENTS.
HER PARENTS GOT ME A "VACATION"
TO THE BAHAMAS.
>> YOU DIDN'T TELL ME IT WAS
FOR YOUR BIRTH --
>> IT'S FOR MY BIRTHDAY, BUT THE
DAY OF THE VACATION IS ON HER
BIRTHDAY.
>> BUT YOU DON'T CALL THAT
DATING?
LIKE, DUDE.
>> AFTER MY BIRTHDAY, YOU KNOW,
A FEW WEEKS GO BY, WE GO ON THIS
TRIP.
THREE DAYS BEFORE WE LEAVE, I
GOT, YOU KNOW, ASKED IF I'D BE
INTERESTED IN THE SHOW.
I LIKE, TELL HER, AND SHE'S
OBVIOUSLY --
>> YEAH.
>> SAD BUT SHE'S ALSO, LIKE,
EXCITED.
AND I WAS THROWN OFF BECAUSE,
LIKE, I THINK IT'S KIND OF,
LIKE, NOT LOGICAL TO HANG OUT
WITH SOMEBODY WHO IS CONSIDERING
DOING A DATING SHOW.
>> IT DIDN'T SEEM LIKE IT WAS A
DATING SHOW TO YOU.
IT WAS JUST FOR YOUR CAREER.
>> IN MY MIND, YEAH.
I WAS GOING HERE FOR A MUSIC
THING.
I TOLD YOU THAT.
>> AND YOU PROBABLY KEPT
REASSURING HER, IT WAS A MUSIC
THING, YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY.
I KNOW THIS IS WHAT HAPPENED.
IT'S WHAT HAPPENED.
>> YEAH.
I -- I TOLD HER IT WAS.
LIKE, THIS WAS GOING TO BE A
REALLY GOOD THING FOR MUSIC.
LIKE, THIS IS LIKE IT.
LIKE, I JUST HIGHLY, HIGHLY
DOUBT THAT THIS COULD ACTUALLY
EVER BE A RELATIONSHIP, THAT I
COULD GO IN THERE AND ACTUALLY,
LIKE, LIKE SOMEONE.
>> WHEN YOU SAID YOU WERE COMING
FOR MUSIC, I THOUGHT, OH, LIKE,
HE DOESN'T KNOW WHAT THIS IS
ABOUT, NOT KNOWING IT WAS, LIKE,
A CONVERSATION ALL THE TIME WITH
ANOTHER GIRL THAT YOU WERE
TALKING TO.
AND IT'S LIKE -- LIKE, THAT
MAKES IT TOTALLY DIFFERENT.
>> YEAH.
AND SHE WAS UPSET BECAUSE I'M
LEAVING.
AND WE'RE SITTING THERE ON THIS
EXTRAVAGANT TRIP.
I'D BEEN DRINKING.
I'M NOT GOING TO MAKE THAT AN
EXCUSE, BUT I HAD BEEN.
AND I TOLD HER THAT I LOVED HER,
AND WHEN I SAID IT, IT DIDN'T
FEEL RIGHT, AND
WAS A MISTAKE, BECAUSE I WAS
LEAVING.
>> JUST SELFISH.
>> IT IS SELFISH.
>> TO EVERYONE.
IT'S SO SELFISH TO HER.
IT'S SELFISH TO ME.
UGH!
>> I KNOW.
I KNOW.
AND SO I LEAVE, AND AFTER I
LANDED IN L.A. AND STARTED THIS
WHOLE THING, THAT WAS, LIKE, A
GOODBYE FOR ME.
WHICH IS NOT A PROPER GOODBYE.
IT'S NOT THE RIGHT WAY TO DO IT,
IT'S NOT CLOSE TO THE RIGHT WAY
TO DO IT.
>> HOW IS IT A GOODBYE?
BECAUSE YOU KNOW I'VE SEEN THE
TEXT MESSAGES.
>> MM-HMM.
IT WASN'T A VERBAL GOODBYE.
>> NO, IT WAS A, "I LOVE YOU,
444."
>> TO ME, I ENDED IT IN MY HEART
AND NOT VERBALLY.
>> HOW?
YOU SAID YOU LOVED HER ON A
PHONE CALL AND A TEXT THE DAY
OF.
>> IT DIDN'T -- I KNOW.
>> LIKE, WHAT DO THOSE WORDS
MEAN TO YOU?
>> I DIDN'T KNOW TILL I MET YOU.
I JUST WAS ON A DIFFERENT PAGE
THAN HER AND I WAS TOSSING
AROUND THREE OF THE MOST
POWERFUL WORDS THAT YOU CAN SAY
TO SOMEBODY LIKE IT WAS JUST
SOME, LIKE --
>> AND IT'S NOT JUST THE WORDS.
YOU SLEPT WITH HER THE NIGHT
BEFORE YOU LEFT.
LIKE, THAT JUST --
THIS IS OBVIOUSLY HUMILIATING
FOR ME.
MY BROTHER'S GETTING MESSAGES.
MY MOM'S GETTING MESSAGES.
AND I -- I HAVE TEXT MESSAGES
FROM OTHER GIRLS FROM THE NIGHT
AFTER I WAS IN NASHVILLE.
THESE TWO GIRLS ARE IN YOUR
APARTMENT.
>> YEAH, WE DIDN'T EVEN KNOW WHO
THEY WERE.
>> WELL, YOU THREW THEM IN A
POOL.
>> I DID.
>> EVERYTHING YOU DO AFFECTS ME.
IF YOU WERE ENGAGED, WHY WOULD
YOU JUST...
ALLOW PEOPLE, GIRLS TO COME TO
YOUR HOUSE AND THEN AT LEAST
JUST NOT TELL ME AFTERWARDS.
>> I GUESS I SHOULD HAVE.
OBVIOUSLY.
I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
>> IT'S VERY HURTFUL, BECAUSE I
AM LIKE, HERE.
I KNOW WHAT I WANT.
I KNOW WHAT, LIKE -- I'VE BEEN
DOING ALL THE THINGS TO BE
PREPARED FOR THIS.
I WAS SO, LIKE, IN THE RIGHT
PLACE FOR IT, AND SO IT SUCKS.
AND NOW TO KNOW THIS, IT'S
LIKE --
>> YOU FEEL BETRAYED?
>> BETRAYED, AND LIKE, HOW WOULD
YOU EVER BE READY TO BE ENGAGED?
LIKE, WHAT?
LIKE, I'VE BEEN DOING ALL
FREAKING STEPS AND, LIKE, KNOW
WHAT I WANTED.
THERE'S JUST A LOT THAT DOES
FEEL LIKE IT'S LIKE CAREER AND
BE NOTICED AND IT FEELS LIKE
IT'S, LIKE, USING ME, OUR
RELATIONSHIP FOR THAT.
>> I DON'T WANT YOU TO FEEL THAT
WAY.
SO HOW -- WHAT DO I HAVE -- WHAT
CAN I DO TO, LIKE, NOT -- LIKE,
WHAT WOULD DEMONSTRATE OTHERWISE
WITH THAT?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T -- I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M ILL.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[APPLAUSE]
>> LOOK, YOU ARE EVERYTHING THAT
I HAVE EVER WANTED AND NEEDED IN
A WOMAN.
I'VE SAID THAT.
I MEANT IT.
AND I KNOW THAT ALL THIS OTHER
STUFF STACKS UP TO MAKE IT LOOK
LIKE I'M NOT TELLING THE TRUTH.
BUT I -- FROM THE BOTTOM OF MY
HEART, I MEAN IT, AND WHATEVER I
HAVE TO DO TO PROVE IT, I'LL DO
IT.
SO PLEASE TELL ME, LIKE, WHERE
DO YOU WANT ME TO GROW?
WHERE DO YOU SEE ME LACKING THAT
YOU WANT ME TO BE BETTER AT?
>> WHAT YOU COULD DO AND WHAT I
WOULD NEED IS 100% HONESTY AND
BEING ABLE TO GET THAT AND TO
RECEIVE THAT.
LIKE, WHAT DID YOU THINK THAT
FIRST NIGHT?
WHAT WAS GOING THROUGH YOUR MIND
WHEN IT WAS, LIKE, SCOTT HAS A
GIRLFRIEND AT HOME.
HE HUNG OUT WITH HER MONDAY.
WHEN ALL THAT HAPPENED?
LIKE, DID IT NEVER, LIKE, CROSS
YOUR MIND TO, LIKE, MAYBE SAY
SOMETHING, TO TELL -- LIKE,
WHAT CROSSED -- DID IT NOT?
>> I DIDN'T HAVE A GIRLFRIEND
THOUGH.
LIKE, SO TO ME, THAT DIDN'T FEEL
LIKE IT WAS A RELATIONSHIP.
BUT NOW, WHEN I LOOK BACK, YEAH,
IT WAS A [BLEEP] THING TO DO,
AND I SHOULD'VE WALKED UP AND
SAID SOMETHING RIGHT THEN AND
THERE, AND I DIDN'T.
I SHOULD HAVE SAID SOMETHING AT
THE FANTASY SUITE, BUT ONCE THIS
STARTED HAPPENING AND I STARTED
SEEING HOW I WAS FEELING ABOUT
YOU, I COULDN'T THINK OF
ANYTHING ELSE.
YOU WERE IT.
THE REASON I HELD BACK DETAILS
THAT I DID IS BECAUSE I WAS
SCARED THAT IF I TOLD YOU, YOU
WOULD WALK AWAY FROM ME.
AND THAT'S, LIKE, THE MOST
COWARD THING TO HEAR, I KNOW,
BUT THAT'S JUST THE TRUTH.
AND I'M SO NOT PROUD OF IT.
IN TURNS, ME PULLING IT BACK
HAS NOW PUT ME IN THIS POSITION.
>> PUT US.
US.
>> I FEEL LIKE I'VE --
>> IT'S NOT JUST YOU.
>> NO.
THAT'S -- THAT'S WHAT I HATE,
BECAUSE I KNOW THAT -- I DON'T
WANT TO CRY ON CAMERA.
>> WHO CARES, JED?
>> I DID SO MUCH SOUL-SEARCHING
WHEN I WAS THERE AND WAS ABLE
TO, LIKE, LEARN MYSELF ON A
WHOLE OTHER LEVEL.
AND IT'S LIKE, WHEN I GOT BACK
HOME --
>> WENT RIGHT BACK TO THE LIFE
YOU WERE IN.
>> I DID NOT FEEL THAT WAY.
>> AND YOU KNOW WHAT ELSE
BOTHERED ME?
>> WHAT?
>> WHEN YOU GOT HOME, AND I
ASKED YOU ABOUT, LIKE, TELLING
YOUR FRIENDS, AND YOU WERE LIKE,
"YEAH, I TOLD THEM I WON."
IT MAKES ME MAD.
>> I GOT ENGAGED TO SOMEONE I
LOVE, WHICH IS A BETTER WAY OF
SAYING IT, BUT I --
>> BUT NOW IT, LIKE, HURTS
WORSE.
BECAUSE NOW, LIKE -- THEN I WAS
LIKE, "WHY DID YOU SAY THAT,
PEOPLE SAY IT, WHATEVER."
BUT NOW IT MAKES ME THINK ABOUT
EVERYTHING AND WHY, AND YOU CAME
FOR THIS AND THIS.
>> IT SOUNDS -- AFTER THAT, AND
THEN SAYING "I WON."
IT'S -- YEAH.
>> AND IT MAKES SENSE NOW WHY
YOUR FAMILY WAS SO...
LIKE...
IT DOES.
AND NOW IT MAKES ME FEEL LIKE,
OKAY, WHEN I WENT TO YOUR FAMILY
AND THEY WERE SO, LIKE,
SKEPTICAL OF IT, NO WONDER.
>> I KNOW THAT I HAD
OPPORTUNITIES TO TELL YOU, BUT
EVERY TIME IT'S LIKE I WOULD GET
THERE AND I WOULD STOP MYSELF
BECAUSE IT FELT LIKE I WOULD
JUST LOSE YOU.
WHICH IS SELFISH OF ME.
NOT THAT THAT'S LIKE --
>> YEAH, BECAUSE I DESERVE TO
KNOW THAT TO MAKE MY FREAKING
DECISION.
YOU ALREADY KNEW HOW I WAS
FREAKING STRUGGLING.
>> I KNOW.
I JUST NEVER MET SOMEONE THAT
MADE ME WANT TO BE A BETTER
PERSON.
>> WELL, THE FIRST WAY TO BE A
BETTER PERSON IS TO BE HONEST
ABOUT YOUR PAST, 'CAUSE NOW
YOUR PAST WAS ACTUALLY CURRENT
AND IT'S NOW IN OUR FUTURE.
IT'S -- IT'S HERE.
THIS DOESN'T GO AWAY.
THIS IS --
IT'S JUST --
[GROANS]
NOTHING IS EVER, LIKE, HOW YOU
PLAN IT TO BE.
BUT, I MEAN, I JUST FEEL LIKE
THIS EXPERIENCE HAS BEEN TAKEN
AWAY FROM ME BECAUSE I DIDN'T
KNOW ALL THE DETAILS.
I WAS BEING TOLD HALF TRUTHS AND
LIES.
AND YOU -- AND YOU -- OH, YOU
WANTED ME TO HAVE CLARITY, AND
CLARITY MEANS --
>> TRUTH.
YOU GOT TO SEE ALL OF ME.
I DIDN'T GET TO SEE ALL OF YOU.
IT IS OF -- ALL OF THE SCARS
THAT HAVE BEEN ON MY HEART IS
BECAUSE OF PEOPLE NOT BEING
HONEST WITH ME.
YOU WERE REALLY SELFISH IN THIS
AND I JUST FEEL LIKE RIGHT NOW
MY DECISIONS, MY CHOICES WERE
ALL TAINTED.
>> I SEE NOW.
AND I DIDN'T SEE [BLEEP].
I DIDN'T SEE [BLEEP].
I WAS LETTING MYSELF JUST DWELL
IN A LIFESTYLE THAT WAS JUST
HURTING ME AND HURTING OTHER
PEOPLE, AND IN TURN IT HAS COME
AROUND TO HURT THE PERSON I
ACTUALLY LOVE AND WANT TO BE
WITH FOREVER.
AND THAT'S SOMETHING I DID NOT
LIE ABOUT AT ALL.
I WANT THAT MORE THAN ANYTHING.
I STILL DO.
I WILL ALWAYS WANT THAT.
I'M SORRY.
I KNOW YOU DON'T WANT TO HEAR
IT, LIKE, OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
BUT LOOK, PLEASE, I'M SORRY.
YOU DON'T DESERVE THIS.
YOU DON'T DESERVE TO FEEL LIKE
THIS.
I'M SORRY.
I WANT TO BE BETTER FOR YOU AND
FOR ME.
I WANT TO BE SOMEONE THAT YOU'RE
PROUD OF, HANNAH.
I NEED -- I NEED SOME GRACE AND
PATIENCE THOUGH, BECAUSE I'M NOT
PERFECT.
>> I HAVE GRACE FOR YOU.
I CAN BE MAD AND I CAN BE UPSET,
BUT I DO HAVE GRACE FOR YOU.
BUT ALSO THIS...
DOESN'T MEAN THE SAME THING.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I SAID YES TO.
>> LOOK, WE SPENT TWO MONTHS
TOGETHER AND WE GOT ENGAGED.
AND THE PERSON THAT I BECAME
OVER THAT TIME SPAN WAS WHO YOU
WANTED, BECAUSE CLEARLY YOU SAID
YES.
AND THAT PERSON IS STILL HERE.
>> I SAID YES, BUT IT HASN'T
BEEN GOOD SINCE THEN.
>> YOU DESERVE TO BE MAD AT ME,
AND I'M SORRY.
>> AND I DESERVE TO BE ABLE TO
QUESTION THIS AND TO NOT KNOW IF
I WANT THIS.
I DON'T KNOW.
[APPLAUSE]
>> IT'S DIFFICULT TO IMAGINE
WHAT HANNAH MUST BE GOING
THROUGH AFTER TRUSTING JED WITH
HER HEART.
THE ENGAGEMENT RING IS ON THE
TABLE ALONG WITH SO MANY
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS.
OUR HANNAH AND JED STILL
ENGAGED?
THIS CAN HANNAH EVER FORGIVE JED
OR IS HANNAH'S TRUST AND JED
BROKEN FOREVER AFTER HIS LIES
AND BETRAYAL?
HANNAH AND JED WILL DRIVE ME
LIVE IT HERE ON STAGE.
WE'LL GET ANSWERS WHEN WE COME
BACK.
[APPLAUSE]
♪
>> WELCOME BACK TO
"THE BACHELORETTE" LIVE FINALE,
WE ARE IN LOS ANGELES TONIGHT.
FOR MANY WEEKS NOW THERE HAVE
BEEN RUMORS FLOATING AROUND
BACHELOR NATION AND THAT JED AND
HANNAH'S RELATIONSHIP MIGHT BE
OVER.
WE JUST WATCHED SHIMEK SHOCKING
FOOTAGE THAT SEEMS TO CONFIRM
MANY OF THOSE REPORTS, SO WHAT S
TRUE?
WHERE DOES THEIR RELATIONSHIP
CURRENTLY STAND?
IT'S TIME TO FIND OUT.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, HANNAH.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> WE LOVE YOU, HANNAH!
>> THANK YOU.
>> HI.
>> HOW ARE YOU DOING TONIGHT?
>> AS GOOD AS CAN BE EXPECTED.
I'M OKAY.
>> WHAT EMOTION IS GOING THROUGH
YOUR HEART AND YOUR HEAD RIGHT
NOW?
>> I JUST CAN'T -- I CAN'T
BELIEVE, UM, THIS IS THE WAY
THIS CONVERSATION IS GOING.
>> YEAH.
THAT'LL EITHER ONE OF US WANTED
IT OR ANTICIPATED IT.
>> MM-HMM.
>> I'M SORRY FOR THAT.
TAKE ME BACK TO THAT DAY WHEN
YOU FOUND OUT, AFTER FILMING WAS
OVER, HOW DID YOU FIND OUT THAT
JED HAD A GIRLFRIEND?
>> WELL, THE FIRST NEWS AHEAD OF
REALLY ANYTHING WAS ACTUALLY
THE DAY AFTER WE GOT ENGAGED.
>> THAT SOON?
>> BUT IT WAS JUST THAT HE
WANTED TO LET ME KNOW, IF
ANYTHING WAS SAID, THERE WAS A
GIRL HE WAS HANGING OUT WITH,
AND I WAS LIKE, OKAY, WHAT DOES
THAT MEAN?
AND DID YOU END IT?
YOU KNOW, I CAN'T EXPECT FOR
EVERY GUY FOR SIX MONTHS NOT TO
HAVE GONE ON A DATE, SO I
THOUGHT, OKAY.
YOU KNOW, BUT ULTIMATELY, HE
TOLD ME, I WAS LIKE, YOU KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED THE FIRST NIGHT,
WAS IT A WEEK, A MONTH, AND HE
TOLD ME IT WAS A WEEK.
HE ENDED IT THE WEEK BEFORE, IT
WASN'T A GIRLFRIEND, JUST
HANGING OUT WITH HER.
I WAS LIKE, WELL, I CAN GET
THROUGH THAT, BUT IT WAS STILL
DISAPPOINTING THAT I HAD TO FIND
OUT THE DAY AFTER I GOT ENGAGED.
BUT THEN I FOUND OUT ABOUT THE
"PEOPLE" ARTICLE COMING OUT THE
NIGHT BEFORE WE WERE ACTUALLY
TOGETHER, AND I THOUGHT IT
WAS REALLY STRANGE WITH THE
INFORMATION I KNEW THAT A
"PEOPLE" ARTICLE WOULD COME OUT.
SO I WAS LIKE, IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU NEED TO TELL ME?
HE WAS LIKE, NO, SHE WASN'T MY
GIRLFRIEND.
AND THEN I JUST WAS LIKE, WHAT
DID YOU EVER TELL HER YOU LOVED
HER?
LIKE, WHY DOES SHE THINK IT'S SO
DIFFERENT THAN YOU?
AND THEN HE SAID, "YEAH, I DID."
AND I WAS LIKE, WELL, NO WONDER,
JED.
AND THEN HE SAID IT WAS ONE TIME
WHEN HE, LIKE, HE SAID IT WAS
ONCE, AND I WAS LIKE, DID YOU
SAY IT AGAIN AFTER THAT?
HE WAS LIKE, YEAH, A FEW TIMES.
BUT THAT'S ALL HE REALLY SAID,
AND THAT WAS ME QUESTIONING IT
AND ASKING HIM QUESTIONS.
AND THEN WE WERE NOT TOGETHER,
AND I GOT THE "PEOPLE" MAGAZINE
ARTICLE SENT TO ME, AND IT'S
REALLY SAD WHEN YOU HAVE TO
CIRCLE THINGS IN A ARTICLE AND
SEND THEM TO YOUR FIANCE.
>> HOW DIFFICULT HAVE THESE LAST
FEW WEEKS BEEN FOR YOU?
>> UM, THEY'VE BEEN REALLY
DIFFICULT.
I THINK I GET -- I HAVE SOLVED
ON THE FLOOR -- SOBBED ON THE
FLOOR, EVERYTHING CAVED IN, AND
EVERYTHING
THAT I THOUGHT WAS TRUE AND REAL
IT WASN'T.
I HAVE BEEN MAD AS HELL.
>> UNDERSTANDABLY.
>> AND JUST QUESTIONING WHAT
HAPPENED, BUT I'VE GOTTEN A LOT
STRONGER THROUGH IT.
>> SO WHERE DOES YOUR
RELATIONSHIP STAND NOW?
>> UM, I AM NOT WITH JED
ANYMORE.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
THE ENGAGEMENTS OVER.
WE ARE NOT TOGETHER.
IT'S JUST -- THAT'S NOT WHAT I
SAID YES TO.
>> I KNOW EVERYONE'S APPLAUDING,
AND I UNDERSTAND WHY EVERYONE IS
A PARTING, BUT I'M SORRY,
BECAUSE WHEN YOU SAY THAT, I SEE
THE HURT IN YOUR EYES, AND I'M
SORRY.
>> YEAH.
WHEN I COME OUT, IT SAID THOSE
THINGS, THE THINGS THAT I SAID
TO HIM ON MY ENGAGEMENT DAY, YOU
KNOW, I THOUGHT THAT WAS MY DAY,
AND I FEEL LIKE THAT WAS TAKEN
FROM ME, AND HOW SPECIAL THAT
WAS.
AND SO IT'S BEEN REALLY HARD TO
GRAPPLE WITH THAT.
BUT I KNOW THAT WHAT I GOT IS
NOT WHAT I EVER WANTED FOR A
LIFE PARTNER, ALTHOUGH IF THAT'S
NOT TO BUILD ON A FOUNDATION OF
TRUTH AND HONESTY, AND I HAVE
LEARNED LEARNED SO MUCH.
>> WELL, I'M SORRY THIS IS WHERE
WE ARE.
JED IS HERE.
YOU ARE ABOUT TO SEE THEM FOR
THE FIRST TIME SINCE YOU GUYS
BROKE UP OVER THE PHONE, SO YOU
HAVEN'T SEEN HIM IN QUITE SOME
TIME.
SO WHEN WE COME BACK, IT JED
WILL SIT NEXT TO HANNAH FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE THEY BROKE UP.
THAT'S NEXT.
[APPLAUSE]
>> WELCOME BACK TO THE DRAMATIC
FINALE OF "THE BACHELORETTE."
I'M HERE WITH HANNAH, WHO JUST
ANNOUNCED THAT SHE HAS BROKEN
THINGS UP WITH JED.
THEY ARE BROKEN UP.
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THEM SINCE THAT
CONVERSATION.
YOU ARE ABOUT TO.
ARE YOU READY FOR THIS?
>> I AM.
>> OKAY.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, IT JED.
[SCATTERED APPLAUSE]
>> CHRIS.
HI.
>> HI.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
>> FINE.
>> JED, THANKS FOR BEING OUT
HERE.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
>> I WANT TO GIVE YOU THE FIRST
CHANCE TO SPEAK AND THE
OPPORTUNITY TO SPEAK ABOUT THIS
RELATIONSHIP, REALLY ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO SAY.
>> WELL, THERE IS A LOT THAT I
WOULD LIKE TO SAY.
FIRST AND FOREMOST, FROM THE
BOTTOM OF MY HEART, I WANT YOU
TO KNOW THAT I'M SORRY, AND I
KNOW THAT APPARENTLY THEY'VE
ALREADY SHOWN WHERE I APOL
APOLOGIZED, BUT ESPECIALLY IN
HINDSIGHT, NOW THAT I FOUND TIME
TO REVIEW MYSELF AND MY PAST AND
MY BEHAVIORS TOWARDS NOT ONLY
YOU BUT OTHER PEOPLE, I FULLY
SEE THAT I WASN'T THE BEST THAT
I COULD BE, AND INTERNS, LACKING
DETAILS TO YOU IN SOME THINGS
THAT YOU DESERVE AND THINGS THAT
YOU WANT, EIGHT --
IT KIND OF IT -- NOT KIND OF, IT
RUINED BUT WE FOUND HERE IN A
PLACE THAT I NEVER WOULD HAVE
EXPECTED TO FIND LOVE LIKE THIS
WITH SOMEONE THAT I WANTED TO
SPEND THE REST OF MY LIFE WITH.
I KNOW YOU FELT THE SAME, AND
I'M SORRY I TOOK AWAY THAT
EXPERIENCE WITH FROM YOU, AND
I'M SORRY THAT THIS HAS HURT
YOUR FAMILY, YOUR FRIENDS,
EVERYONE, MY FAMILY.
I'M SORRY.
I'M RESPONSIBLE FOR THIS.
I WILL OWN UP TO THAT ALL DAY.
WHEN I WAS REACHED OUT TO ABOUT
DOING THE SHOW, I JUST NEVER
WOULD HAVE DREAMED THAT I WOULD
MEET THE PERSON THAT I WANT TO
SPEND THE REST OF MY LIFE WITH
ON A REALITY TV SHOW.
I NEVER WOULD HAVE FATHOMED IT.
I WISH I WOULD HAVE KNOWN MORE
ABOUT IT WHEN I SH SHOWED UP, BI
DIDN'T.
I NEVER WOULD HAVE DREAMED YOU
WOULD BE HERE.
AGAIN, I'M SORRY.
>> JED, I KNOW YOU WERE
SURPRISED THAT YOU FOUND LOVE,
SO WHEN YOU DID, AFTER THE
ENGAGEMENT, WHEN YOU GUYS HAD
THAT MOMENT, WHY DIDN'T YOU JUST
COME CLEAN?
>> I WAS ACTING OUT OF FEAR
INSTEAD OF OUT OF LOVE AND
RESPECT FOR YOU.
I WAS SCARED TO LOSE YOU.
I WASN'T SURE HOW ANY OF IT
WOULD BE TAKEN.
THOUGH I FELT LIKE I HAD CLOSURE
ON MY PART, I COULD SEE THAT
THERE WASN'T ON OTHER PEOPLE'S
PARTS, AND THAT WAS MY FAULT.
BUT I HELD OUT BECAUSE I WAS
SCARED TO LOSE YOU.
>> HANNAH, WHAT'S GOING THROUGH
YOUR MIND RIGHT NOW?
>> UM...
SO MESSED UP.
IT'S JUST SAD.
BUT I APPRECIATE YOUR APOLOGY.
AND I KNOW THAT IT'S HURT ME A
LOT, BUT I KNOW THAT THIS HAS
NOT BEEN EASY FOR YOU AND YOUR
FAMILY, AND I KNOW CRITICS CAN
BE HARD.
I HAVE SOME ELSE ALSO.
AND WHAT YOU DID WAS NOT RIGHT
AND NOT GOOD, BUT I DID FALL IN
LOVE WITH YOU, AND I KNOW THAT
THAT PERSON IS IN THERE, AND I
JUST, YOU KNOW, HOPE THAT FROM
THIS YOU WILL BE HONEST AND
LEARN AND GROW INTO THE MAN THAT
I DO BELIEVE THAT YOU CAN BE FOR
WHOEVER IN YOUR FUTURE.
[APPLAUSE]
>> EMOTIONS ARE RUNNING HIGH.
WE ARE GOING TO TAKE A QUICK
BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL
CONTINUE WITH HANNAH AND JED.
STICK WITH US.
♪
[APPLAUSE]
>> WELCOME BACK TO THE LIVE
FINALE OF "THE BACHELORETTE."
I'M HERE WITH HANNAH AND JED WHO
HAVE BROKEN THINGS OFF, THERE
ENGAGEMENT IS OVER,
UNFORTUNATELY.
I KNOW EMOTIONS ARE RUNNING
HIGHER TONIGHT.
JED, I WANT TO GO BACK TO YOU.
HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT HANNAH N
NOW?
>> OH.
THE SAME THAT I FELT SINCE I GOT
DOWN ON ONE KNEE.
I NEVER REALLY -- LIKE I SAID, I
NEVER FATHOMED FALLING IN LOVE
THERE AND I NEVER FATHOMED IT
BEING ON THE LEVEL IT WAS.
SOMETHING I NEVER FELT IN MY
LIFE, TO SEE MYSELF WITH SOMEONE
FOREVER FOREVER.
TO BE MARRIED, TO HAVE A FAMILY,
TO DISCUSS THAT KIND OF THING.
LIKE, I'VE NEVER HAD THAT LEVEL
OF A RELATIONSHIP, AND THAT CAME
WITH YOU SO NATURALLY.
AGAIN, THAT'S ANOTHER REASON
THAT I REGRET ALL THIS, SO MUCH
REGRET MY DECISIONS.
AND I WISH, YOU KNOW, IT WAS
DIFFERENT, AND I WISH THAT I
COULD CHANGE THE PAST, BUT I
CAN'T.
BUT MY LOVE FOR YOU, I DON'T
THINK IT WILL EVER LEAVE ME.
IT JUST IS THERE TO STAY.
>> SO YOU ARE STILL IN LOVE WITH
THIS WOMAN?
>> I ALWAYS WILL BE.
>> HANNAH, WHAT ARE YOUR
FEELINGS?
>> UH, I AM -- I'M NOT TRYING TO
PUNISH YOU, BUT MY FEELINGS HAVN
THAT TRUST WAS BROKEN, MY
FEELINGS REALLY JUST WERE BROKE
WITH THAT.
AND I DON'T -- I DON'T LOVE YOU
LIKE THAT ANYMORE.
AND I'M NOT --
AND IT'S NOT SOMETHING TO CLAP
ABOUT.
IT'S SAD.
I KNOW YOU'VE HURT ME, BUT I'M
NOT TRYING TO HURT YOU RIGHT
NOW.
BUT IT'S JUST NOT WHAT EITHER --
AND A BUT IT NEEDS TO START A
RELATIONSHIP ON, LIES, AND NOT
FEEL CONFIDENT IN THAT, AND I
WANT TO FEEL REALLY CONFIDENT IN
MY FOREVER.
>> SO THIS IS OVER?
>> YES.
>> I'M SORRY FOR BOTH OF YOU.
JED, I'M GOING TO GIVE YOU THE
FINAL WORD HERE.
>> AGAIN, I JUST WANT YOU TO
KNOW THAT I DO LOVE YOU.
I'M SORRY THAT YOUR FEELINGS
HAVE CHANGED DUE TO MY ACTIONS.
AND YOU DESERVE THE WORLD AND
YOU DESERVE TO BE HAPPY, AND
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED THAT FOR YOU
WHETHER IT WAS ME OR SOMEONE
ELSE.
I'VE TOLD YOU THIS.
AND I HATE THAT IT'S NOT ME, BUT
I HOPE THAT GOD BESTOWS A SUPER
HAPPY LIFE FOR YOU AND THAT YOU
CONTINUE TO BE THE AMAZING WOMAN
THAT I KNOW YOU ARE, THAT YOUR
FRIENDS KNOW YOU ARE, AND THAT
AMERICA KNOWS YOU ARE.
AND I'LL BE THERE FOR YOU IN
ANYWAY THAT I CAN.
>> THANK YOU.
I WANT THAT FOR YOU TOO.
>> YOU BOTH HAVE BEEN THROUGH A
LOT.
AND, JED, I KNOW A LOT OF IT WAS
SELF-INFLICTED, BUT I DO
APPRECIATE YOU COMING OUT HERE
AND SITTING NEXT TO HANNAH AND
DEALING WITH ALL OF THIS IN
PUBLIC.
SO THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE.
>> WELCOME BACK.
WE ARE HERE IN LOS ANGELES
BEFORE WITH OUR BACHELORETTE
HANNAH WHO JUST SOUGHT JED FOR
THE FIRST TIME SINCE THEY BROKE
UP THE ENGAGEMENT.
I KNOW THAT WAS DIFFICULT.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
>> UM, I AM -- YOU KNOW, IT'S
BEEN REALLY HEARTBREAKING, FOR
SURE, AND I'VE QUESTIONED A LOT
OF THINGS AND MY EXPERIENCE, BUT
I AM REALLY PROUD OF MYSELF,
BECAUSE IN THE PAST, I'VE BEEN
IN RELATIONSHIPS WHERE THERE
WASN'T ALWAYS TRUST AND THERE
WASN'T ALWAYS HONESTY, AND I
WOULD STICK WITH THAT.
AND I WOULD WANT -- NEED A MAN,
BUT THEN I WOULD FORFEIT MY
HAPPINESS.
BUT I HAVE REALIZED THAT I DON'T
NEED A HUSBAND, I WANT A
HUSBAND.
I DON'T NEED ONE.
AND I'M REALLY, REALLY PROUD OF
THE WOMAN THAT I'VE BECOME
THROUGH ALL THIS, BECAUSE I AM
HELLA STRONG.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> I THINK THE CROWD IS PROUD OF
YOU, I'M INCREDIBLY PROUD OF
YOU, THAT SUCH STRENGTH, POISE,
COMPETENCE, YOU ALWAYS
IMPRESSED.
BUT UNFORTUNATELY, THERE IS ONE
GUY WE HAVEN'T HAD A CHANCE TO
TALK ABOUT, HE HAS BEEN
OVERSHADOWED BY ALL OF THIS, AND
HE DESERVES SOME RESPECT,
DESERVES TO BE TALKED ABOUT AS
WELL, AND THAT'S TYLER.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
YOUR CONNECTION WAS UNDENIABLE,
CHEMISTRY WAS STRONG, AND I KNOW
THAT GOODBYE THAT DAY IN CRETE
WAS BRUTAL FOR YOU.
>> MM-HMM.
IT'S HARD BECAUSE THAT DAY I
WANTED IT TO BE HAPPY AND I WAS
REALLY STRUGGLING WITH HOW I
FELT.
BUT, YEAH, I'VE BEEN REALLY
GRIEVING THAT RELATIONSHIP.
>> WE ARE ABOUT TO BRING HIM
OUT.
>> YEAH.
>> WHAT'S IT GOING TO BE LIKE TO
SEE HIM AGAIN?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS I'M GOING TO FIGURE THAT
OUT.
I MEAN, THOSE FEELINGS JUST
DIDN'T GO AWAY.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
WHAT?
[LAUGHS]
>> HANNAH?
>> CHRIS?
>> ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL SEE WHAT HAPPENS HERE.
LET'S BRING HIM OUT.
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN, TYLER.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> HEY, BOY.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> I'M GOOD, HOW ARE YOU?
>> I'M AMAZING.
>> I FEEL LIKE I SHOULD JUST
LEAVE.
IT'S LIKE THE DAMN BEATLES JUST
WALKED IN HERE.
GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU, CHRIS.
>> UM...
[CROWD CHEERING]
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME YOU HAVE
SEEN EACH OTHER SINCE THAT DAY
IN GREECE.
>> SHE LOOKS AMAZING.
>> HE LOOKS OKAY.
>> HOW DOES IT FEEL FOR YOU TO
BE BACK HERE AND SEE HER AGAIN.
>> I'M EXCITED TO SEE HER.
YOU KNOW, I WAS LOOKING FORWARD
TO THIS DAY ACTUALLY.
IT WAS A TOUGH BREAKUP AND IT
WAS HARD, BUT I HAVE SO MUCH
RESPECT FOR YOU AND I LOVED
WATCHING THE SEASON, HOW
POWERFUL AND STRONG YOU'VE BEEN.
WATCHING YOU KNOW, WAS LIKE
[...]
>> IT'S OKAY, WE'RE JUST LIVE ON
ABC.
>> SORRY, MOM.
YOU ARE JUST SO POWERFUL AND SO
STRONG.
>> HOW HARD IS IT TO WATCH
POST-ENGAGEMENT, TO KNOW SHE WAS
CONTINUING ON THIS LIFE WITH
JED?
>> YEAH, YOU KNOW, WHEN SHE TOLD
ME THAT IT WAS NOT ME AND IT WAS
JED, I WAS IN FULL SUPPORT, I
FELT LIKE SHE WAS GOING TO BE IN
GOOD HANDS.
IT'S BEEN TOUGH TO SEE HER GO
THROUGH WHAT SHE HAS GONE
THROUGH, BUT SHE IS A FIGHTER,
ONE OF THE STRONGEST PEOPLE I
HAVE MET, THE WORLD IS HERS.
AND I KNOW THAT.
>> SWEET.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> THAT DAY, YOU WERE SURE.
YOU WERE READY TO GET DOWN ON
ONE KNEE, WEREN'T YOU?
>> THAT DAY WAS ONE OF THE MOST
EXCITING DAYS I'D EVER
EXPERIENCED.
THAT MORNING, I WOKE UP AND WAS
THROWING UP, I WAS SO NERVOUS.
BUT IT WAS A GOOD NERVOUS.
IT WAS LIKE -- EVERY FIRST GAME
OF THE YEAR WHEN I WAS PLAYING
FOOTBALL, I WOULD THROW UP.
I HAD THAT SAME WITH YOU, IT WAS
A GOOD NERVE, BUT THEN TO GO ON,
AND I WAS LIKE THE HAPPIEST
LITTLE KID GROWING UP THAT
MOUNTAIN GETTING READY TO SEE
Y
YOU, AND I WAS READY TO TAKE
THAT STEP WITH YOU, AND IT
WAS -- THAT FEELING I HAD GOING
UP TO SEE IT IS SOMETHING I
LONGED FOR AND HOPE TO HAVE
AGAIN.
>> HANNAH, WHAT'S GOING THROUGH
YOUR HEAD RIGHT NOW?
>> UM...
WELL, I -- I KNOW THAT WITH
TYLER IT'S BEEN -- HE'S BEEN SO
SUPPORTIVE AND SO RESPECTFUL OF
ME NOT JUST, LIKE, ON OUR
JOURNEY TOGETHER BUT EVEN
AFTERWARDS.
AND I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S JUST, LIKE, THAT
RELATIONSHIP, A RELATIONSHIP WAS
REAL TO ME AND SPECIAL, AND
EVERYTHING I SAID, I MEANT AND I
FELT, AND IT DIDN'T JUST GO
AWAY, AND I STILL MIGHT LIKE, I
HAVE FEELINGS.
[CROWD CHEERING]
[GROANS]
>> WHAT ARE THOSE FEELINGS?
>> I'M REALLY CONFIDENT IN WHO I
AM AND BEING ON MY OWN AND
GROWING AND REALLY TAKING
EVERYTHING THAT I HAVE LEARNED
AND WHAT I WANT IN THE NEXT
RELATIONSHIP, BUT, I DON'T KNOW,
I MEAN, I'VE ALWAYS SAID --
OH, GOD CREATED [LAUGHS]
YEAH
I WANT SOMEBODY TO BE BOLD, AND
I AM BOLD, AND I MAKE BOLD MO
MOVES.
SO, I MEAN, I -- YOUR AN
INCREDIBLE GUY, AND I'M A SINGLE
GIRL.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
SO...
YOU KNOW, IF SO, I DON'T KNOW, I
JUST THOUGHT MAYBE WE COULD GO R
A DRINK AND JUST HANG OUT.
>> I WOULD LOVE TO.
JUST TELL ME WHEN, I'M HERE.
>> DID YOU JUST ASK TYLER OUT ON
A DATE?
>> I -- I THINK I DID.
>> A CARD?
>> I WILL SEND A DATA CARD.
A HELICOPTER, A BALLOON.
>> NO HORSES.
>> JUST SO WE ARE CLEAR, WE ARE
GOING TO HAVE A GO AT THIS.
>> I THINK WE NEED TO JUST,
LIKE, BE NORMAL PEOPLE AND JUST
SEE AND HANG OUT.
>> TAKE IT ONE STEP AT A TIME.
>> JUST HAVE A DRINK.
>> IT'S BEEN A WHILE.
>> I THINK I SPEAK FOR EVERYBODY
WHEN I SAY WE CAN 'SHIP THIS.
GUYS, GIVE IT UP FOR TYLER AND
HANNAH!
A PERSONAL CONGRATULATIONS, JADE
AND TANNER, WHO MET ON THE
BEACH, WELCOME THEIR SECOND
CHILD.
SHE ACTUALLY, SHE GAVE BIRTH TO
THE HER BABY BOY IN HER MASTER
CLOSET LAST NIGHT, TRUE STORY.
GOD BLESS, GUYS.
WE WISH YOU THE BEST.
DON'T FORGET TO WATCH HANNAH
LATER TONIGHT ON "JIMMY, LIVE."
TO
OUR STUDIO AUDIENCE, THANK YOU
ALL, THANK YOU.
AND TO YOU, BACHELOR NATION, WE
COULDN'T DO IT WITHOUT YOU.
FOR EVERYONE THAT HAS BEEN A
PART OF THIS ONE, I'M CHRIS
HARRISON, GOOD NIGHT.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
♪